{
    "id": "ee1ba12826d04bb590d31a7d73381838",
    "title": "Gap Fills Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "I told him ................................. be late.",
            "description": "We put not before the infinitive. ",
            "answers": [
                "to not",
                "not to"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "The teacher asked us .................................. our assignments.",
            "description": "Imperatives are reported with a to-infinitive. ",
            "answers": [
                "that we submit",
                "to submit"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "She asked me if I ..................................... her before.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "saw",
                "have seen",
                "had seen"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "He told us ...................................... on time.",
            "description": "Imperatives are reported with to-infinitive. ",
            "answers": [
                "that be",
                "to be"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "He told me ......................................... for him.",
            "description": "Imperatives are reported with to-infinitive. ",
            "answers": [
                "to wait",
                "wait",
                "waiting"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "The teacher asked if I ..................................... the answer.",
            "description": "When the main verb is in the past tense, the subordinate verb, too, will most probably be in the past tense. ",
            "answers": [
                "know",
                "knew",
                "had known"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I asked the manager if I .................................. leave early.",
            "description": "When the main verb is in the past tense, the subordinate verb, too, will most probably be in the past tense. ",
            "answers": [
                "can",
                "could"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "They asked me ........................................ interested in the offer.",
            "description": "We use the normal word order in indirect questions - that means the subject goes before the auxiliary. ",
            "answers": [
                "if was I",
                "if I was"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I told him ........................................ not coming.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "that I was",
                "that I am",
                ""
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "She said that no one .......................................... forward to help her.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "came",
                "had come",
                "has come"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "He asked me what I ...................................... do if I lost my job.",
            "description": "When the main verb is in the past tense, the subordinate verb, too, will most probably be in the past tense. ",
            "answers": [
                "will",
                "would",
                "can"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "They encouraged her .................................... another attempt.",
            "description": "Encourage is followed by object + to-infinitive. ",
            "answers": [
                "make",
                "to make",
                "making"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        }
    ]
}